PERSONAL INFO

Address

Bangalore, INDIA

Phone

+91 984 539 8483

F-mail

sjeleven11@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/sjeleven11

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis, MO, USAMaster of Business Administration (MBA) Olin Business School

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India

Master of Business Administration (MBA) -Shailesh J. Mehta School of Management

Bangalore University, India

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), in Computer Science & Engineering

SKILLS

- ✓ InfoSec, Cybersecurity, Identity & Access Mgmt.: Okta, SailPoint
- ✓ Cloud Security & Audit: Azure, AWS
- ✓ Data Security & Data Management: DOMO
- ✓ Project Management: Jira
- ✓ Al and ML for Decision-makers and Leaders
- ✓ GenAl: ChatGPT, Stable Diffusion XL, DALLE-3, Midjourney
- ✓ Cybersecurity GenAl
- ✓ Risk Management

CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ ISO/IEC 27001:2022 Lead Auditor
- ✓ Cloud Security (CCSK V4) Certified
- ✓ Cloud Auditing (CCAK) Trained
- ✓ AWS Identity and Access Mgmt.
- ✓ PRINCE2 Foundation & Practitioner
- ✓ ITIL V3 Expert Level Certified
- ✓ COBIT 5 Foundation Certified
- ✓ Al and ML for Decision-makers and Leaders
- ✓ Cybersecurity GenAl

SARAVANAN JAYARAMAN

Senior leadership in CX And Value Creation

PROFILE

Enthusiastic Technology leader and goal-oriented service delivery lead with 24+ years of IT industry experience including oversight of infrastructure, cybersecurity and data management services.

Strategic thinker and negotiator dedicated to customer satisfaction with focused delivery of technical solutions. **Proven track record of C-suite engagement** with an extensive personal contact base.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

August 2024 - Present Senior Director | Head of India Operations at OpSec Security, India

- Successfully implemented identity management solutions for multiple clients, resulting in improved security and compliance.
- Developed and maintained policies and procedures that ensured regulatory compliance.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to drive business outcomes and improve identity management processes.
- Support C-suite leadership in translating business vision into Operational strategy.
- Head India delivery operations for Brand Protection, Anti-Fraud, Anti-Piracy businesses.
- Design policies, overseeing customer service and implementing process efficiency and solutions.
- Budgeting and cost management/optimization.

December 2014 – August 2024 Associate Director at Concentrix India Services, Bangalore, India

Highly experienced Identity Access Management (IAM) leader with expertise in designing and implementing IAM solutions, stakeholder management, and driving business outcomes. Proven track record of delivering complex IAM projects and leading teams comprising 100+ resources spread across four geographies (India/US/Canada/Phil) by providing strategic support to win and retain clients for \$10 billion Corporation.

- Designed and implemented IAM solutions for clients across various industries
- Collaborated with stakeholders to understand business requirements and develop IAM strategies
- Developed and maintained IAM policies, procedures, and standards

- Implemented identity governance, access management, and authentication solutions
- Worked with cross-functional teams to ensure IAM solutions met business requirements

Technical Skills: Identity Governance, Access Management, Authentication Protocols (SAML, OAuth, OpenID Connect), Cloudbased IAM solutions (AWS IAM, Azure Active Directory)

December 2003 – December 2014 Manager, ITO Enterprise Services at Hewlett-Packard Enterprise Services, Bangalore, India

Progressively promoted based on technical and leadership results, earning accolades for ability to direct production engineering/operations team in enterprise managed services and support.

- Consulting, Design, Solution Implementation of Data Center Services, End User Computing, Enterprise Systems Monitoring and Support.
- Managed engineering/operations teams in Data Center Services, End User Computing, Enterprise Systems Monitoring domains using tools like HP Open View Operations (OVO), Microsoft SCOM/SCCM, O365, and SharePoint.
- Led innovation through automation and helped file patents for HP.
- Manage a team of 40+ IT Solution Architects and SMEs assigned on the infrastructure projects/programs.

August 2003 – December 2003 Technical Support Specialist at 24/7Customer, Bangalore, India

July 2002 – August 2003 Technical Support Executive at Sutherland Technologies, Chennai, India

February 2001 – December 2001 Software Engineer – Trainee at ProdEx Technologies, Chennai, India

CORPORATE SOCIAL RESPONSIBILITY (CSR) ACTIVITIES

- **ESG (Environment, Social and Governance) -** Participated and led teams in Carbon Sequestration Challenge project total efforts equated to 400K+ kgs of potential carbon emissions avoided.
- Save SOIL Earth Buddy Volunteered in planting of 100K+ trees sampling project as part of revitalization of the India's Cauvery River and transform the lives of 84 million people.